Andrea Pazzaglia

Manager
Data Science & AI

Contact

•

(+39) 333 9939556



andrea.pazzaglia91 @gmail.com



Milano, Italia



linkedin.com/in/andreapazzaglia-ph-d-521946158

Education

2020

PhD cum Laude,

Energy and Nuclear Science and Technology

- Politecnico di Milano

2016

Master's Degree 110L/110,

Nuclear Engineering

- Politecnico di Milano

Key Skills

End-to-End AI System Development

Machine Learning

Artificial Intelligence

Cloud Computing

Story telling

Languages

Italian - Mother tongue English - C1

Profile

PhD in engineering, experienced with the theoretical, numerical and statistical modelling in several fields. Well-versed in various programming languages (including Python, C++, Matlab, Labview), softwares (including Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Latex), and operating systems (Windows and Linux). Used to handle end-to-end technical projects and to manage junior resources.

Professional Experience

Sept 2023 - Present

Milano

Manager in Data Science & AI at PwC (selected projects)

- Custom Generative AI tools development (e.g. chatbot), based on Large Language Models (OpenAI), for a famous newspaper.
- HR advanced analytics for Energy & Utilities company: classification of misused contracts using Large Language Model (BERT, HuggingFace).

Dec 2020 - Aug 2023

Milano

Data Science Senior Associate at PwC (selected projects)

- Self-supervised pattern extraction from customers of a trading platform, through multi-modal multi-task variational autoencoders.
- Data Science guidelines definition (coding, MLOps, governance) for Energy & Utilities industry.
- Long-term budget forecasting and industrialization on cloud (Google Cloud Platform) for Telco industry.

Oct 2016 - Nov 2020

Milano

Research Fellow at Politecnico di Milano (selected projects)

- Study of the laser-plasma interaction with numerical simulations and theoretical models.
- Carry out experiments of laser-plasma acceleration in collaboration with international facilities.
- Writing publications in peer-review international journals and presenting results in international conferences.

Certifications and Publications

- AWS Certified Machine Learning (2022) <u>link</u>
- Professional Data Scientist DataCamp (2021) <u>link</u>
- AWS Certified Developer Associate (2021) link
- Pazzaglia A. et al. "A theoretical model of laser-driven ion acceleration from nearcritical double-layer targets" Communications Physics (2020) link
- See other publications on LinkedIn profile